

Marco Santonastaso

CONTACT

m.santonastaso@protonmail.com <u>https://santonastaso.me</u> <u>https://github.com/marnas</u> +(44) 7384167923

INTRODUCTION

Dedicated and motivated IT Specialist with a degree in Engineering & Computer Science and a strong programming background, finding his way around the cloud through a DevOps lens, utilising his problem-solving skills and deep analytical thinking.

KEY SKILLS & COMPETENCIES

- · Multiple coding language background (OOP mainly) Java, JavaScript, C, Python, Go, Node.js
- · Network knowledge and Infrastructure as Code experience Terraform, AWS, Ansible
- Confident with containerization and container orchestration Docker, Kubernetes
- · Windows & UNIX knowledge SysAdmin experience -abundant experience using the command-line
- · Strong team-worker & self-driven learner
- Keen attention to details

WORK EXPERIENCE

AltoStack

November 2019 — Present

Junior DevOps Engineer

At AltoStack, we're revolutionising the way businesses innovate and grow through our technology products and consultancy services by providing a much more efficient, experienced and affordable way to operate on the Cloud and adopt DevOps.

We unlock innovation for enterprise and scale-up organisations by making cloud, DevOps and agile adoption fast, secure and simple.

We have helped many enterprise and scale-up organisations:

- Adopt Cloud Native Infrastructure
- Adopt DevOps & Continuous Delivery
- Adopt Container Technology

G-Research

July 2018 — September 2019

Identity and Access Management Developer

Focus on delivering solution design & development of products oriented to Identity management within the Company, ensuring access control and security maintenance.

Digital identities lifecycle management (Joiner, Mover, Leaver) with Sailpoint IdentityIQ automation development and integration with third party software (GIT, JIRA, Active Directory).

Rest API implementation backend security oriented - CI/CD Pipeline structure design (Jenkins).

Responsible for Terraform integration with Okta Cloud Identity & implementation of provider plugin in Go.

Main technologies utilised:

- Terraform, Go, Python
- · Java Beanshell, XML

Marco Santonastaso

FullStack Developer

Startup aimed at offering a compare platform for 3D printing all over the world, helping users to find and choose among the best deals, while giving more visibility to providers vetted by the company.

The Website is based on MeteorJS, utilising MongoDB. Responsible for both frontend and backend side services functionality. Involved in diagnosing and rectifying performance issues through code reviewing.

Highly interested in security-oriented backend infrastructure, ensuring vulnerabilities associated with compromised application security and data protection are prevented and detected on time.

Main technologies utilised:

- · NodeJS Meteor React Python
- Version Control System GIT

EDUCATION

Engineering in Computer Science

University of Rome "La Sapienza"

- · Software Development Programming
- · Algorithms Knowledge Cost Analysis
- · Network Infrastructure Communications

Scientific High School

School of Caserta (Italy) "Alessandro Manzoni"

- · Maths Physics
- · Natural sciences Chemistry

ADDITIONAL SKILLS & INTERESTS

- · Languages: Italian Native, English fluent.
- · Archlinux user Linux filesystem knowledge, Raspberry PI owner, guitar player, yoga.

September 2013 — May 2017

September 2008 — July 2013